Guide to the Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1838-2021 (bulk 1852-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series I. Printed Ephemera, 1840-2017
  - Trade Cards
    - "Series 515. Onkel Toms Hutte," Germany: Vertheidigung der freien Fluchtlinge, circa 1910; [7 cards] (Folder 1.69)
    - Stetson's Big Double Uncle Tom's Cabin Co., circa 1890s (Folder 1.70)
    - Tobacco companies, circa 1880s; [3 cards] (Folder 1.71)
    - "Topsy Tablet, no. 418,", undated (Folder 1.72)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, "The Adams & Weslake, Wire Gauze, Non-Explosive Stove,", circa 1890s (Folder 1.73)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Dodge & Atkins, 1881 (Folder 1.74)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, E. S. Sullivan's Black Diamond Combination, circa 1880s; [11 cards] (Folder 1.75)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, "Eliza's Escape,", undated (Folder 1.76)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, J. & P. Coats, undated (Folder 1.77)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Woolson Spice Co., circa 1894-1895; [4 cards] (Folder 1.78)
    - "Veritable extrait de viande Liebig: l'case de l'Oncle Tom,", [after 1885]; [6 cards] (Folder 1.79)
- Series II. Sheet Music, circa 1852 - circa 1925
  - Adams, John S., "I Am Going There, or the Death of Little Eva," Boston: Oliver Diston, 1852 (Folder 11.1)
  - Bayha, Chas A., "At Uncle Tom's Cabin Door," composed by Rubey Cowan, New York: York Music Co., undated (Folder 11.1)
  - Collier, Mary A., "The Death of St. Clare," Boston: Oliver Ditson, circa 1852 (Folder 11.1)
  - Collier, Mary A., "Eva's Parting," composed by F. James, Boston: G.P. Reed & Co., circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.1)
  - Comer, Thomas, "Our Homestead is Surely the Sweetest on Earth," Boston: G. P. Reed, circa 1852 (Folder 11.2)
  - Cook, Eliza, "Little Topsy's Song," composed by Asa B. Hutchinson, Boston: Oliver Ditson, circa 1853; [2 copies] (Folder 11.2)
  - Cook, Eliza, "Topsy Neber Was Born," composed by S. Stanley, New York: The Amphions, circa 1854 (Folder 11.2)
  - [Cook], Eliza, "Uncle Tom's Glimpse of Glory," composed by Frank Howard, Boston: E. H. Wade, circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.2)
  - D'Albert, Charles, "Topsy Quadrille," London: Chappell & Co., undated (Folder 11.2)
  - Duncan Sisters, "I Never Had a Mammy," from Topsy and Eva, New York: Irving Berlin, Inc., circa 1925 (Folder 11.3)
  - Duncan Sisters, "Rememb'ring," New York: Irving Berlin, Inc., circa 1925 (Folder 11.3)
  - "Eva!," Toronto and Clifton: The Toronto News Company, undated (Folder 1.80)
  - "Eva's Song of the World to Come," composed by W. Wills Taylor, London: G.H. Davidson, Peter's Hill, Doctors' Common, undated (Folder 11.3)
  - Foster, Stephen C., "Massa's in de Cold Ground," New York: Firth Pond & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.3)
  - Howard, George C., "Eva to Her Papa," New York: Horace Waters, circa 1853; [2 copies] (Folder 11.3)
  - Howard, George C., "Oh! I'se So Wicked," New York: Horace Waters, circa 1854; [2 copies] (Folder 11.3)
  - Howard, George, C., "St. Clare to Little Eva in Heaven," Boston: Oliver Ditson, 1850s; [2 copies] (Folder 11.3)
  - Howard, Mack and Frank H. Clark, "Topsy," composed by Billy Baskette and Billy Waldron, Chicago: Duncan Sisters Music Publishers, circa 1924 (Folder 11.4)
  - Ikeler, Otto P., "Eva's Dream," Rohrsburg, PA: Columbia Co., circa 1901 (Folder 11.4)
  - Jefferys, Charles, "George's Song of Freedom," composed by Stephen Glover, London: C. Jefferys, 1850s (Folder 11.4)
  - Jefferys, Charles, "Topsy's Song," composed by Stephen Glover, London: C. Jefferys, [1855?] (Folder 11.4)
  - "Kibble and Martin World's Greatest Uncle Tom Cabin," Chicago: Will Rossiter, circa 1911 (Folder 11.4)
  - "Kibble and Martin World's Greatest Uncle Tom Cabin," Chicago: Will Rossiter, circa 1913 (Folder 11.4)
  - Linley, George, "Little Eva," arranged by J.P. Weston, Boston: White, Smith & Company, circa 1878 (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 1: Eva," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2: The Slave Mother," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 3: Evangeline," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 5: Emmeline & Cassy," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 6: A Tear for Poor Tom," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.5)
  - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. ?: Liberty," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.5)
  - "Lucy Neale," arranged by O. H. Normino, London: Monro & May, undated (Folder 11.6)
  - "Mort Steece Mammoth Uncle Tom's Cabin," Chicago: Will Rossiter, 1910s; [very brittle] (Folder 11.6)
  - Nichols, R. S., "Uncle Tom's Cabin Songs," composed by William Cumming, Cincinnati, OH: W.C. Peters & Sons, circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.6)
  - "The Old Cabin Home," composed by T. Paine, Boston: Henry Tolman & Co., circa 1858 (Folder 11.6)
  - Russell, Henry, "Topsy's Polka," London: Musical Bouquet, 1850s (Folder 11.7)
  - Russell, Henry, "Uncle Tom's Cabin Quadrille," London: Musical Bouquet, 1850s (Folder 11.7)
  - Russell, Henry, "Davidson's Uncle-Tom Quadrille," London: G.H. Davidson, Peter's Hill, Doctor's Commons, circa 1860 (Folder 11.7)
  - Rutledge, John T., "De Old Church Yard in De Lane, or Darling Minnie Gray," Cincinnati, OH: F.W. Helmick, circa 1875 (Folder 11.7)
  - Rutledge, John T., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," East Liverpool, OH: W. L. Thompson & Co., circa 1878 (Folder 11.7)
  - "Slave Life, or, Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 1: Nelly Bly," edited by Charles Jefferys, London: C. Jefferys, circa 1852 (Folder 11.7)
  - "Stetson's Old Reliable Uncle Tom's Cabin Songster," Chicago: Harold Rossiter Music Company, circa 1924 (Folder 11.8)
  - Stonehouse, James, "Evangeline," composed by George Hargreaves, Liverpool: Hime & Son, circa 1852 (Folder 11.8)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Early In De Morning," composed by Thomas Comer, Boston: G.P. Reed & Co., 1852 (Folder 11.8)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Still With Thee. Sacred Song," composed by P.A. Schnecker, New York & London: Edward Schuberth & Co., circa 1897; [2 copies] (Folder 11.8)
  - "Terry's Uncle Tom's Cabin Song Album," Chicago & New York: Harold Rossiter Music Company, circa 1915 (Folder 11.8)
  - Tierney, Harry Austin, "'Uncle Tom's Cabin' Rag," New York: [Joseph] W. Stern & Co., circa 1911 (Folder 11.9)
  - "Uncle Tom," composed by H. Swift, New York: W. Hill, circa 1852 (Folder 11.9)
  - Wetmore, W.J., "Uncle Tom's Cabin Song," New York: Millets Music Saloon, circa 1852 (Folder 11.9)
  - Whittier, John G., "Little Eva; Uncle Tom's Guardian Angel," composed by Manuel Emilio, Boston: John P. Jewett & Company, 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.9)
  - "William H. Kibble's Original Uncle Tom's Cabin Songster," Chicago: Harold Rossiter Music Company, circa 1920 (Folder 11.10)
  - Winner, Septimus, "The 'Contraband' Schottische," Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co., circa 1861 (Folder 11.10)
  - Wood, Henry, "Poor Uncle Tom," composed by A. Sedgwick, New York: William Vanderbeek, 1852 (Folder 11.10)
  - Woodbury, I.B., "Uncle Tom's Lament for Eva," Boston: Oliver Ditson, circa 1852; [2 copies] (Folder 11.10)
  - Covers
    - Carpenter, J.E., "The Birds and the Angels (Dred's Song)," composed by John Blockley, London: Cramer Beale & Co., [1857] (Folder 11.11)
    - Carpenter, J.E., "The Language of the Heart (Nina's Song)," composed by John Blockley, London: Chappell & Co., [1857] (Folder 11.11)
    - Carpenter, J.E., "The Shower of Rose Leaves," composed by L. Williams, London: B. Williams, circa 1850s (Folder 11.11)
    - Glover, Stephen, "The Tom-Tit Polka, companion to the Topsy Polka," London: Charles Jefferys, [1856?] (Folder 11.11)
    - Hunt, C.W., "Uncle Sam: The Great Slave Song," composed by Frederic Archer, London: Foster & Lenfant, [1870] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "Eva's Parting Words," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "George's Song of Freedom," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "Mother, Mother, You Are Weeping!," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "Poor Tom!," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1853 Sep?] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "The Sea of Glass," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852] (Folder 11.11)
    - Jefferys, Charles, "Sleep My Child, Let No One Hear You," composed by Stephen Glover, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852] (Folder 11.11)
    - Kitchen, R., "Bright Star of Thy Home," composed by Alfred Mullen, [1852] (Folder 11.12)
    - Lord, Fanny E., "Eva at Sunset," London: Stannard & Dixon, [1852/3] (Folder 11.12)
    - Le Duc, Carl, "Uncle Tom's Cabin Quadrilles," London: C. Sheard Musical Bouquet, 1850s (Folder 11.12)
    - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2: The Slave Mother," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.12)
    - Linley, George, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 3: Evangeline," London: Chappell & Co., circa 1852 (Folder 11.12)
    - Mitchell, J., "St. Clare," composed by C. H. Gamblin, London: Robert Cocks & Co., [1852/3] (Folder 11.12)
    - Nicholls, P. R., "Topsy's Lament," London: H. Tolkien, circa 1850s (Folder 11.12)
    - O'Grady, Caroline, "Eva's Dream," London: Charles Jefferys, 1850s (Folder 11.12)
    - Tully, J. H., "Topsy's Polka," London: Charles Jefferys, 1852 (Folder 11.12)
    - "Tully's True Topsy Quadrille," Lyceum Theatre, London: Charles Jefferys, [1852/3] (Folder 11.12)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin Quadrille," arranged by Jean Rosier, London: Harry May, circa 1850s (Folder 11.12)
    - Wagner, "The Octoroon Waltz," London: Boosey & Sons, undated (Folder 11.12)
- Series III. Visual Media, 1852 - circa 1927
  - Lantern Slides
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, London: W. C. Hughes, undated; [28 color glass slides in a wooden box] (Box 8)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, New Bedford, MA: Cherry & Co., Inc., [1890s?]; [2 glass slides in paper box] (Box 8)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, New York: T. H. McAllister, undated; [12 black-and-white glass slides] (Box 9)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, New York: T. H. McAllister, undated; [6 color glass slides] (Box 9)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Philadelphia: Williams, Brown and Earle, [1890s?]; [3 color glass slides] (Box 9)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin in Three Chapters," Chapter 1, Primus Junior Lecturers' Series, circa 1880s; [7 glass slides] (Box 3)
  - Lithographs
    - Dred by Harriet Beecher Stowe, illustrations for J. K. Green edition, circa 1856 (Folder 1.81)
    - Hunt, A., "Eva paint out the Happy Land," engraved by E. E. Jones, undated (Folder 1.82)
    - Portraits of female authors, circa 1910s (Folder 1.83)
  - Lithographs, hand-colored
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Cassey's Sorrows," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1853 Jan 8 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Cassy's Happier Days," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1852 Dec 30 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Eliza," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1852 Oct 27 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Eliza's Escape," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1853 Feb 10 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Emmeline Sold," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1852 Nov 10 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Eva and Topsy," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1852 Nov 1 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Eva's Farewell," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1853 Mar 9 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Eva's Forebodings," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1852 Nov 10 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "George & Eliza," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1853 Mar 21 (Folder 12.1)
    - Corbaux, Louisa, "Topsy At Her Tricks," London: Stannard & Dixon, 1853 Jan 12 (Folder 12.1)
    - Régnier, Claude and Adolphe Jean-Baptiste Bayot, “Uncle Tom's Cabin. George et Elisa Chez les Quakers,” Paris: Lemercier, undated; [No. 4] (Folder 12.2)
    - Decan and Destouches, "La case du Père Tom (Kantukuy)," Paris: Fontaine editeur, circa 1850s (Folder 13.5 (Oversize))
  - Paintings
    - Unknown artist, "7. Onkel Tom schreibt mit Hilfe Evangelinens an seine Familie" [Uncle Tom writes to his family with Evangeline's help], undated; [pencil and watercolor, matted] (Folder 7.1)
    - Unknown artist, Topsy and Eva, undated; [pencil and watercolor, matted] (Folder 7.2)
    - Unknown artist, Uncle Tom reading to Eva, undated; [pencil and watercolor, matted] (Folder 7.3)
    - Unknown artist, Uncle Tom with his family, undated; [pencil and watercolor, matted] (Folder 7.4)
  - Photographs
    - Al. W. Martin's Uncle Tom's Cabin Company train, undated (Folder 1.84)
  - Posters
    - "Anthony & Ellis Mammoth Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.," Boston & N.Y.: Forbes Co., [1890s]; [74 x 48 cm] (Folder 14.6 (Oversize))
    - "Charles Harrington's American Combination Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 4753," Hill, Siffken & Co. Grafton Works, London & Liverpool, undated; [76 x 50 cm] (Folder 14.7 (Oversize))
    - "Ed. F. Davis' Uncle Tom's Cabin: Uncle Tom bidding his children farewell," Erie Litho. Co., Erie, PA, circa 1895; [80 x 61 cm] (Map Case - Drawer 37)
    - "Kroger Babb presents Harriet Beecher Stowe's Uncle Tom's Cabin," Kroger Babb & Associates, undated (Folder 12.3)
    - "Little Cordelia Howard, the Child of Nature, Aged 5 Years. In the Character of Eva," New York: C. Currier Print, undated (Folder 12.4)
    - "Onkel Toms Stuga," Konserthus - Biografen, Kinna, [193?] (Folder 12.5)
    - "Parsons & Pool's Famous Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin Company,", undated; [printed on linen] (Folder 13.6 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Seer's Print, Union Square, N.Y. (the death of Little Eva), 1870s; [68 x 44 cm] (Folder 14.8 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, a COLORAMA Features Release with a cast of thousands. Told by Raymond Massey,", circa 1927 (Folder 12.6)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin: Marks, No. 2223," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [71 x 54 cm] (Folder 14.9 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Middaugh's New Orleans Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.," Erie Litho. Co., Erie, PA, undated; [55 x 85 cm] (Map Case - Drawer 37)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2220," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [71 x 54 cm] (Folder 14.9 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2224," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [71 x 54 cm] (Folder 14.9 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2307," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [107 x 72 cm] (Map Case - Drawer 33)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, No. 2308," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [107 x 72 cm] (Map Case - Drawer 33)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin: Topsy, No. 2221," Ackermann-Quigley Litho. Co., Kansas City, undated; [71 x 54 cm] (Folder 14.9 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin in Print," exhibition poster, Vassar College, 2004; [84 x 54 cm, foam board] (Map Case - Drawer 37)
- Series IV. Realia, 1852-2021, undated
  - Bracelet charms
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Pugster Italian Charms, circa 2005; [3 charms] (Folder 1.85)
  - Brass token
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, MA-2026, 5124, So. 60th St,", undated (Folder 1.86)
  - Card Games
    - "American Women Authors Card Game," U.S. Game Systems Inc., 1995 (Box 3)
    - "Game of Authors Playing Cards,", circa 1900s (Folder 2.8)
    - "The Game of Star Authors," New York: McLoughlin Bros., 1887; [ 13 x 17 cm, box with 72 cards and instruction booklet] (Box 3)
    - "The Game of Uncle Tom," Parkhurst, RI: V. S. W., 1852 (Folder 2.9)
    - "Inspirational Women Trivia Game," Ridley's Games, 2021; [9 x 10 cm, box with 80 cards] (Box 3)
    - "The Instructive Game of Authors," Philadelphia: Porter and Coates, circa 1880; [box of cards] (Box 3)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin playing cards, Spain: Fournier Cards Museum, 2004 (Folder 2.10)
  - Ceramic figurine
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe (no. 2314 of 9500), Great American Women Series, United States Historical Society, undated; [15 cm] (Box 4)
  - Ceramic jar
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated; [10 cm] (Box 4)
      Description: Depicts Uncle Tom's death at the hands of Simon Legree.
  - Ceramic mugs
    - "Eva Dressing Uncle Tom,", undated; [8 cm] (Box 4)
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, 200th anniversary event, Bowdoin College Special Collections and Archives, circa 2011 (Box 4)
  - Ceramic pitchers
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated; [15 cm, cream] (Box 4)
      Description: A cream-colored ceramic pitcher depicting two scenes from Uncle Tom's Cabin, including Eliza and Harry's escape across the ice from Mr. Haley.
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated; [18 cm, yellow] (Box 4)
      Description: A yellow ceramic pitcher depicting two scenes from Uncle Tom's Cabin, including Eliza and Harry's escape across the ice from Mr. Haley.
  - Ceramic Plates
    - "Death of Eva,", undated; [12 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Eliza Crossing the Ice,", undated; [12 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Eva Dressing Uncle Tom,", undated; [18 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Eva Wreathing Tom,", undated; [12 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Evas Todt," Schramberg, undated; [20 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Jacksonville, The Gateway to Florida," Vernon Kilns, undated; [27 cm, blue transfer] (Box 5)
    - "La Case De L'Oncle Tom, La Soeur de Georges condamnée au fouet," Bordeaux: J. Viellard & Cie, undated; [21 cm, green and black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "La Case De L'Oncle Tom, Non Cassy, Dieu nous voit," Bordeaux: J. Viellard & Cie, undated; [21 cm, green and black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "La Case De L'Oncle Tom, On a pas besoin de toi ici, Va-t'en," Bordeaux: J. Viellard & Cie, undated; [21 cm, green and black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "No. 3, Elisa Traverse L'Ohio Sur La Glace," Leboeuf, Milliet & Cie (Creil et Montereau), circa 1852-1876; [21 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "No. 12, Mort De L'Oncle Tom," Leboeuf, Milliet & Cie (Creil et Montereau), circa 1852-1876; [21 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Prayer Meeting in Uncle Tom's Cabin,", undated; [20 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Sale of Harry,", undated; [12 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "The Pearl of Orr's Island," Etruria, England: Wedgwood Pottery, undated; [24 cm, blue transfer] (Box 5)
    - "The Stowe House Brunswick Maine," England: Old English Staffordshire Ware, undated; [18 cm, blue transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Tom Versucht Seiner Frau Zu Schreiben," Schramberg, undated; [20 cm, black transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Topsy Bringing Flowers to Eva,", undated; [12 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Dresden, [Ontario]," Can. Art China, Collingwood, [Ontario], undated; [26 cm, 22k gold leaf edge] (Box 5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Eliza's Escape,", undated; [16 cm, black transfer with painted flowers] (Box 5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Eva Dressing Tom,", undated; [18 cm, green transfer] (Box 5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, The Death of Uncle Tom,", undated; [16 cm, black transfer with painted flowers] (Box 5)
  - Ceramic Sculptures
    - Eva, undated; [9 cm] (Box 4)
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, undated; [9 cm] (Box 4)
    - "Harriet Beecher Stowe's House," signed by John Putnam, undated; [8 cm] (Box 4)
      Printed on bottom: "John Putnam's Heritage Houses, Harriet Beecher Stowe's House, Made [in England?]"
    - Uncle Tom, undated; [10 cm] (Box 4)
    - Uncle Tom, undated; [18 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: Uncle Tom reads a book while sitting next to a basket of round fruits or vegetables.
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, undated; [15 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: The two characters sit under a branch while Little Eva holds a book.
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, undated; [20 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: Uncle Tom wears a string of flowers around his neck and holds a pale yellow hat. At the base of the statue is inscribed: "Uncle Tom"
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, undated; [20 cm] (Box 6)
      At the base of the statue is inscribed: "Eva gaily laughing was hanging a wreath of roses round Tom's neck."
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, undated; [23 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: Eva holds a red flower and Uncle Tom wears a white suit jacket with gold edging.
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, circa 1860; [27 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: Uncle Tom wears a wreath of flowers and a dark blue jacket. The base of the statue is inscribed: "Uncle Tom." The sale label on the bottom of the statue reads: "Victorian Staffordshire Uncle Tom & Eva, ca. 1860"
    - Uncle Tom with Eva, undated; [27 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: Uncle Tom holds a rose and a book and wears an open white shirt and red and white striped pants while Eva stands next to him.
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, cabin model, handmade, undated; [10 cm, brown] (Box 4)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, cabin model, handmade, undated; [9 cm, green] (Box 4)
    - [Uncle Tom's Cabin?], house sculpture, Norwich Collection, circa 1986 (Box 4)
      Inscribed: "Norwich Collection, [copyright] 1986 A.L."
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, unidentified Black woman, undated; [17 cm] (Box 6)
      Description: A woman wearing a white dress with pink flowers, a white bonnet, and blue shoes while sitting next to a basket of round fruits or vegetables.
  - Cereal box cut-outs
    - Mickey Mouse in Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated (Folder 2.11)
  - Embroidery transfer sheet
    - "Eva and Topsy,", undated (Folder 12.7)
  - Handkerchief
    - Whittier, John G., "Little Eva Song. Uncle Tom's Guardian Angel," composed by Manuel Emilio, undated; [Borders on right and left sides] (Folder 12.8)
    - Whittier, John G., "Little Eva Song. Uncle Tom's Guardian Angel," composed by Manuel Emilio, undated; [Borders on all sides; 2 copies] (Folder 12.8)
  - Kleenex facial tissue box
    - Women Who Changed America, Harriet Beecher Stowe, circa 1980 (Box 3)
  - Metal plate
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, R. B. Schiefner, undated; [23 cm, covered in a cracked paper applique] (Box 5)
  - Metal tin
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, circa 1896; [16 x 12 cm] (Box 3)
  - Miniature books
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, circa 2007 (Folder 2.12)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, International Dollhouse Miniatures, circa 2010 (Folder 2.13)
  - Paper bag
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe House museum store, undated (Folder 2.14)
  - Paper napkin
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe House wallpaper design, undated (Folder 2.15)
  - Printing plates
    - Newsprint advertisements for Uncle Tom's Cabin (1969), directed by Geza Radvanyi, undated (Folder 7.5)
  - Sugar packet
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, Monarch International Foods, 1977 Summer (Folder 2.16)
  - T-Shirt
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, cream, undated (Box 3)
  - Toys
    - Doll, Harriet Beecher Stowe, Hallmark American Spirit Collection, circa 2000; [20 cm] (Box 3)
    - Jigsaw puzzle, "Uncle Tom's Cabin" / Map of the United States, circa 1880; [wood with applied paper lithograph] (Folder 7.6)
    - Jigsaw puzzle, Uncle Tom's Cabin, wooden box, undated (Box 3)
      Side of the box reads: "Uncle Tom's Cabin and Map of the United States."
    - Paper dolls, Uncle Tom's Cabin, circa 1900 (Folder 2.17)
    - Paper dolls, Uncle Tom's Cabin, Boston Sunday Globe, Art Supplement, 1896 Jan 26 (Folder 2.18)
    - Paper theatre, Uncle Tom's Cabin, New York: J. V. Sloan & Co., 1906; [2 chromolithograph sheets] (Folder 12.9)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, cardboard plantation play set, undated; [3 folders] (Folders 2.19-2.21)
  - Wallpaper Panels
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1. The Sale of Little Harry," with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)
      Note: Based on the sheet owned by the Stowe Center, which has the same six panels.
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, 2. Eliza Crossing the River," with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," 3. Uncle Tom's departure, with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, 4. The Defence," with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, 5. The Death of Eva," with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)